episode where I cover three things, what's on my mind this week, recommended reading
this week's curation will get you thinking about your own systems before you close
your laptop for the weekend. I'm your host, Joe Casabona, and here's what's on my
mind for August 14th, 2026.
Am I wrong about AI generated YouTube thumbnails? You likely know how I feel about
using AI for creative work. I don't like it.
I fear too many business owners, including myself at times, suffer from ai, brain
rot, from relying too much on it for certain tasks
for a while now, one of those tasks was creating YouTube thumbnails. I worry they
don't look real. And some I've seen look nothing like me.
I am so bullish on this that I've told my thumbnail designer to never use AI on them,
especially when it comes to images of me or my brand assets like my hat.
But maybe
that doesn't matter to get the click.
I mean, it seems to me creating YouTube thumbnails is closer to a science than an
art. There are countless tools that will evaluate a thumbnail and score it based
If all we're trying to do is appease an algorithm, then what's wrong with using a
computer program to do it?
But the thing is, we're not right.
We're trying to convince human beings to think our video is worth watching.
And some AI thumbnails are simply God awful. I mean, I will link this in the show
notes, but if you're watching the video, look at this one.
The most generous opinion I could muster of this is that it's a convincing projection
that I don't want to use it on my channel.
But again,
does it matter?
I know it doesn't look exactly like me, but it is close enough,
and if it convinces people to click, then it's done the job, right? I mean, if you
look at Mr. Beast's thumbnails, they look like a super weird version of him. But
of him.
I am experimenting with them. I am using them on my channel. I'm usually ab testing
them against what my thumbnail designer
creates, and I'm not getting enough hits to have anything conclusive.
But
while I believe in strong opinions loosely held,
I might be holding onto this one a little tighter.
I'd love to know what you think about this. Let me know@streamlinedfeedback.com.
play it on the show unless you ask me to keep it anonymous.
So that's what's on my mind for this week. Let's move over to recommended reading,
everybody I know who's doing curation this week has mentioned this. Over on platformer,
Casey Newton has a great article about Mark Zuckerberg's AI manifesto. And I, I do
wanna give a shout out to my friend and listener, Liz, for sending this to me.
The truth is,
anything that references Game of Thrones is good in my book, but the analogy between
dragons and AI or dragons and super intelligence that Newton makes is salient
and very clever.
I'm not gonna spoil any more of it. I strongly recommend you read this.
He's also uniquely positioned to make the points he does. As a trustworthy, independent
journalist and someone close to the tech industry,
I tend to default to what's the ulterior motive of this billionaire. And it's nice
that Newton is informed enough to state it so plainly. So I will have that as a link
in the show notes along with everything I'm talking about as usual. But I strongly
recommend you read this. I'm a subscriber. I'm not a paid subscriber. I'm very close
though.
but I am subscribed to Platformer now and,
Doon. I finished this far too short series mdo earlier this week, and I thought it
was delightful. I'm also a couple of years late to the party.
It's two seasons, six episodes long. Each season is about the length of a musical,
right? So each season is six episodes, 12 episodes total, and it's fun and catchy
and a testament to great talent.
It was also a really good palette cleanser after House of the Dragon wrapped up.
The worst part about the show is that it didn't get renewed for season three, which
I read. They had like 25 songs written, and they were gonna focus on musicals of
of the Week, but I'm deciding to expand the scope of it.
called Daily Call Debrief, and it does a few things. It runs daily and it gathers
any calls I had recorded in Google Meet or Fathom. It summarizes the calls and adds
those summaries to obsidian,
it adds my action items to Todoist, which surfaces them in my task manager. Something
I check every day. And something I added this week
is it adds coaching calls and discovery calls the transcripts,
it, it takes them and adds them to my voice of customer folder so I can pull from
them. When I'm working on marketing copy or positioning or anything like that.
AI call recorders
is one of the great use cases
for AI in my opinion
that data
and since you were on the call and present, presumably you have already consumed
the primary source and you're not just relying on the summary for important details.
One thing I like to have AI do as well, something I got from,
Christian who was a guest on this podcast back when I had guests, is have it come
up with questions based on the calls. And here's the exact prompt Christian gives
answered, would yield some kind of transformative, genuinely novel, impactful insight.
The thing that I added was, please make reference to the primary source material
asked me a question that was so accurate, it physically hurt me. So,
if you
are thinking about your systems and you don't know where to start,
where to start and exactly how to start.
You can find that over at streamlined fm slash quiz. But that's it for this episode